JIAXU LIU

 $(+61)451873040 \diamond jiaxu.liu@anu.edu.com$ $(+86)13591398665 \diamond ljxw88@163.com$

SHORT BIO

I'm a senior year undergraduate student at Australian National University pursuing a bachelor's degree of Advanced Computing(honour), prior to joining the double degree program, I was doing bachelor of computer science at Shandong University in China.

My current research basically focuses on machine learning(in particular variational techniques) under the supervision of Prof. Tom Gedeon, I'm also doing some summarizing works relating to the graphical models which is currently under review by my thesis co-supervisor Mr. Zhenyue Qin. My research interests include variational inferences, probabilistic graphical models, optimization(convex & nonconvex), etc.

EDUCATION

Australian National University

July 2019 - Present

Bachelor of Advanced Computing(Honours)

ANU College of Engineering and Computer Science

GPA: 6.0/7.0(ANU), 4.0/4.0(WES)

Shandong University

2017 - 2019

Bachelor of Computer Science

School of Mechanical, Electrical & Information Engineering

Listed in "Double First-Class" universities. Project 985 & 211

GPA: 80.17/100

EXPERIENCE

Academic Tutor

July 2020 - Present

Australian National University

Casual Academic Staff, TA for course COMP3600/6466 (Algorithms). Responsibilities include:

- Facilitator in weekly interactive tutorials, assist students with lab exercises and course content
 - Responsible for creating&marking assignment, quizzes, and examinations
 - As a sessional academic staff, receive feedback from students, help improve teaching quality

Development Intern

Jan 2019 - Feb 2019

IIFOX Shanghai

Responsibilities include:

- Maintaining Customer relationship management (CRM) system and develop new functions within ASP.NET framework
- Cooperate with engineers in the deployment department and implement the system in various environment

Associate Representative of Students' Association

Jun 2018 - Jun 2019

Shandong University, School of Mechanical, Electrical & Information Engineering

ACM-ICPC School Team Member

Jan 2018 - Jun 2019

Shandong University, ACM-ICPC School Team

PUBLICATION

Norm-KL-Divergence: A Remdy For Negative Monte Carlo Estimated Values Of KL-Divergence

Under Review

Authors: Zhenyue Qin, Jiaxu Liu, Yang Liu, Saeed Anwar, Pan Ji, Tom Gedeon

Conference: International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, & Signal Processing (ICASSP)

Declarative Residual Network For Robust Facial Expression Recognition

Aug 2020

Authors: Ruikai Cui, Josephine Plested, Jiaxu Liu

Conference: International Conference on Neural Information Processing (ICONIP)

AWARD & ACCOMPLISHMENTS

The 10th Shandong technology festival —— The 9th Shandong Collegiate ACM Programming Contest, The Excellence Award

May 2018

Organization: Shandong Computer Federation

The 9th Lanqiao Programming Contest, Shandong Provence, C/C++ Programming Pollegiate A Group, The Province Second Award

Apr 2018

Organization: Talent exchange center of Ministry of industry and information technology

CCCC Group Programming Ladder Tournamen, National Finals, The Second Award

Mar 2018

Organization: Zhejiang University

Shandong University (weihai) ACM Programming Contest 2018 "New Stars", The Silver Award

Mar 2018

Organization: Shandong University

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming & Skills(Proficient) Programming & Skills(Familiar) Selected Course Accomplishment C++, C , Python, Data Structure, Algorithm, Pytorch Ada, HTML/PHP, C#, Java Convex Optimisation, Advanced Algorithm, Computer Vision, Bio-inspired Computing, Probabilistic Graphical Models